

# Kevin Falencik Front End Developer

### **About me**

I'm a 28 years old, Polish front-end developer, living in Edinburgh, Scotland. I'm very passionate about web technologies, with more than 10 years of experience in the field. I started as a more full-stack developer but recently decided to shift my focus to front-end technologies as it better suits my creative side. For more details about me please visit my digital resume page at - kevinfalencik.netlify.com

# Work experience

**Front End Developer** / Kin+Carta (former AmazeRealise) Edinburgh, Scotland

From March 2018 to March 2020

- Developing and maintaining a number of projects using front-end frameworks
- Vue.js, Nuxt.js, React, Angular
- Experience in deploying sites using Netlify
- Writing clean CSS/SASS
- Writing DRY pure JavaScript (ES6) code
- Experience implementing Firestore database and Contentful API
- Maintaining constant communication with the clients
- Experience using Jira, Fogbugz, Slack, Github, Gitlab and similar
- Travelling to different locations for meetings and on-site client work
- Developed a number of side projects during spare time

## Lead developer (full-stack) / Starbit Edinburgh, Scotland

From November 2013 to March 2018

- Developing and maintaining websites on Drupal 7 & Wordpress
- Writing clean CSS/SASS
- Organising database structures in MySQL
- Developing custom PHP modules and views
- Custom jQuery/AJAX plugins
- LAMP Unix server
- GIT
- Maintaining constant communication with the clients
- Leading a small team of developers

# **Drupal web developer (full-stack)** / **Droptica (former Advanteo)** Gdansk, Poland

From November 2011 to January 2013

- Developing and maintaining websites on Drupal 6 & 7
- Writing clean CSS/SASS
- Remote work
- Organising database structures in MySQL
- Developing custom PHP modules and views
- LAMP Unix server
- GIT

- math Date of birth 02/27/1991
- ♦ 67/2 Lorne Street, EH6 8QG Edinburgh
- ★ Kfalencik@gmail.com
- +44 7961 276427
- % kevinfalencik.netlify.com

# **Computer skills**

Semantic HTML5

CSS/SCSS/SASS/LESS

JavaScript (ES6)

React, Redux

Vue.js, Nuxt.js

**Angular** 

#### **Interests**

**Books and movies** 

Cycling

Video and board games

Music and playing guitar

**Doodling and tattooing** 

#### Other skills

- Windows, Mac OS, Linux
- Adobe Illustrator, Photoshop, GIMP
- GIT, SVN, SourceTree, GIT Bash
- NPM, Gulp, Grunt
- JSON, Firebase/Firestore, Contentful
- ¡Query, AJAX, Axios
- PhpMyAdmin, MySQL
- LAMP, WAMP, XAMPP, Acquia Dev Tools
- WCAG2 AA accessibility standards
- Slack, Jira, Fogbugz, Github, Gitalb

#### **Education**

Information Technology / University of Gdansk Poland

From September 2011 to December 2011

(Unfinished)

Computer Scientist specializing in Network Applications / Complex of

technology and communication schools Gdansk, Poland

From September 2007 to May 2011

Lower secondary school / Gimnazjum #1 Tczew, Poland

From September 2004 to June 2007

# **Side projects**

Realise Aircon 3000 Web app created using Nuxt.js and Firestore database. Each desk at the "dev side" of AmazeRealise office was able to vote if it's either too hot or too cold. It also showed the current 3 air condition units status. This helped us track people temperature preferences during summer of 2019. I have also created a chrome extension and a mobile app (react-native + expo) for easier access.

Web app - <a href="https://realise-aircon-3000.netlify.com">https://realise-aircon-3000.netlify.com</a> Chrome ext - <a href="https://tiny.cc/26ygiz">https://tiny.cc/26ygiz</a>

**Type IT - Word spelling game** Started as a simple jQuery side project, then turned into a test subject of my js frameworks comparison presentation. Objective of the game is to spell as many words as possible before the time runs out. I have also created a version of this game using react-natvie and expo.

¡Query version:

https://type-it-jquery.netlify.com

Vue.js version:

https://type-it-vue.netlify.com

React version:

https://type-it-react.netlify.com

Angular version:

https://type-it-angular.netlify.com

**Codepens** There are multiple, smaller but also fun bits and bobs of code, that I did in my spare time on codepen - <a href="https://codepen.io/kfalencik">https://codepen.io/kfalencik</a>. Please do have a look!